<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Parsia&#39;s Den</title>
    <link>http://parsiya.net/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Parsia&#39;s Den</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 20:22:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://parsiya.net/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hugo?</title>
      <link>http://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-Why-Hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 20:22:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-Why-Hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed (well no one reads this so I am fine), I have moved from &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I have been trying to make this change for a while but due to laziness and some other matters it did not happen. I am going to talk about why I decided on the move and what I did. In then ext post I will talk about my migration from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;octopress-the-bad-parts:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;Octopress the Bad Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octopress had become so slow. Although I do not have many blog posts, they are usually long and contain images and code. Also it does not support incremental generation which means that every time I wanted to push my blog, I had to re-create the blog from scratch. I could live with this because I only do new posts every once in a while so waiting a couple of minutes before deploying the website is not inconvenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My main problem was during content creation. Every time I wanted to look at my changes I had to wait 30 seconds and then refresh the page manually to see the changes. This became very inconvenient. I started creating my posts in a local markdown editor (with preview support) and then copy/pasting it into the actual markdown file and looking at the result. However, modifying posts still took a lot of time and effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Octopress was written in Ruby. I am not a developer but I have written Ruby code (some of which are closer in your everyday lives than they appear &lt;code&gt;;)&lt;/code&gt;) but as you can see in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://parsiya.net/blog/2015-07-26-Image-Popup-and-Octopress/&#34; title=&#34;Image Popup and Octopress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;imgpopup plugin post&lt;/a&gt;, creating plugins for Octopress was a pain for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;octopress-the-good-parts:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;Octopress the Good Parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hafiz the famous ancient Persian poet said &amp;ldquo;عیب می جمله چو گفتی هنرش نیز بگو&amp;rdquo; which basically means that you should talk about the strengths [of something] after you have ranted about the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean theme: The Octopress classic theme is great. I really like it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does what it claims. You can install it using a gem and set up your posts and it is probably good to go. Most probably you will not encounter a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts can be written in Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a lot of plugins for everyday use out of the box. There are plugins for code, images, videos and tweets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that Octopress is a bad static website generator? Not really but it did not work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-wanted:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;What I Wanted&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be reasonably fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code and image caption plugins. Most static website generators supports code highlight by default but I really like code and image captions. Either it should be supported or I could create my own plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have the Octopress classic theme or a similar theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows me to migrate my posts from Octopress. In other words, support writing posts in Markdown. This is supported by almost all static website generators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and almost everything would work without problems but creating plugins would be a pain. After all Octopress is built on top of Jekyll. Some call it a fancy front-end for Jekyll but I disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shopped around looking for static website generator and my final choices were &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.getpelican.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pelican:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;Pelican&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2013/05/07/migrating-from-octopress-to-pelican/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; titles &amp;ldquo;Migrating from Octopress to Pelican&amp;rdquo; by Jake Vanderplas was really helpful and that was one of the reasons I almost chose Pelican and even modified most of my posts to work in Pelican.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pelican is reasonably fast. I was amazed after I changed something in my post and saved and the page in browser auto-refreshed with changes within a few seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is written in Python. Nowadays I write most of my code in Python but creating the plugins were a pain. I fiddled with them for a few days and gave up after I could not create what I wanted.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a figure with caption plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/tree/master/better_figures_and_images&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;better figures and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no code caption plugin. I tried creating my own but I got lost. The reason was that because the code is not a one liner (it has an opening tag and closing tag with code int between), I had to create a Markdown pre-processor. There is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/blob/master/liquid_tags/include_code.py&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Include_code plugin&lt;/a&gt; that creates a highlighted code block with caption but it only supports pulling from a file. That would not work for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone has already done it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/duilio/pelican-octopress-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/duilio/pelican-octopress-theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I only needed to modify some tags but it mostly worked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pelican was a really good fit. However, the pains that I had to go through in order to create a codeblock with captions plugin (Markdown preprocessor what?), made me skip this and go for Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;hugo:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will talk about why I chose Hugo and the migration in length in the next post. But for now let&amp;rsquo;s see if Hugo is a good fit for my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is reasonably fast. Similar to Pelican when I modified a Markdown file, the browser auto-refreshed and I could see the changes in a few seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo had neither. However it supports &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/extras/shortcodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt; and I could create both in a few minutes. I will talk about what I did and how I did it in the migration post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo does not have the classic Octopress theme and this was a big weakness compared to Pelican. But as you can see I made my own. It was a good exercise in learning about the inner workings of Hugo and &lt;code&gt;css&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not only Hugo supports Markdown, it has an &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/commands/hugo_import_jekyll/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;import Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; module which works for Octopress. It seems like a good number of people have moved to Hugo from Jekyll because there are a good number Jekyll themes ported to Hugo. For a list of Hugo themes you can visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugoThemes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion:6e4dd96c118f451aabe1dc11a2f8644f&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo fit my criteria better than Pelican (or any other static website generator that I encountered during my search). It did not have the Octopress classic them but I created my own. In the next blog post I will talk about my migration from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- links --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>