<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/tags/octopress/</link><description>Recent content in Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:52:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/tags/octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archive Page in Hugo</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-14-archive-page-in-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:52:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-14-archive-page-in-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a re-hash of my answer on Hugo forums about creating a custom archive page. You can see the answer &lt;a href="https://discuss.gohugo.io/t/blog-archives-page/2577/16" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creating a custom archive page in Hugo is pretty simple. I think there are better ways to do this but this works as of version 0.15.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Octopress to Hugo</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 22:58:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/" title="Why Hugo?">my previous post&lt;/a> I talked about why I moved from Octopress to Hugo. You can also see the last archive of my Octopress blog (previously a private repo on Bitbucket) on &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Octopress-Blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">github&lt;/a> and this is the new site. If I had wanted to use an already existing Hugo theme, it would have not taken more than a few hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I am going to talk about how I managed the migration and any interesting things that I encountered in the process. I will also introduce the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/hugo-octopress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo-Octopress&lt;/a> theme (you are looking at it), which is the classic Octopress theme ported to Hugo. If you like what you see, please go ahead and use it. If there are any issues please use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Hugo-Octopress/issues" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Github issue tracker&lt;/a> or contact me another way. I will try my best to fix them but please remember that I am not a developer and do not know much about css :).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Hugo?</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 20:22:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>As you may have noticed (well no one reads this so I am fine), I have moved from &lt;a href="http://octopress.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Octopress&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo&lt;/a>. I have been trying to make this change for a while but due to laziness and some other matters it did not happen. I am going to talk about why I decided on the move and what I did. In then ext post I will talk about my migration from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MarkDown and Cookie Clicker</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-15-markdown-and-cookie-clicker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-15-markdown-and-cookie-clicker/</guid><description>Markdown looks like an easy-ish language to start (probably not so easy to master of course). Although compared to writing LaTeX source, it is a breeze. During my last year at JHU I started writing the reports and what not directly into LaTeX, I think using MarkDown for blogging and MS Office at work is going to take away my old skills.
On a side note, I am now up to around 500 million cookies per second (CpS) in Cookie Clicker.</description></item><item><title>Hello Octopress</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-14-hello-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-14-hello-octopress/</guid><description>** Octopress is here **
To be honest setting it up took a while (I had this feeling that I should set it up on my host but well let's say I am a n00b and am allowed to make mistakes) :D
Now I have to learn markdown which is probably a good thing, unless I can write blog posts in different formats. Note to self: search to see if we can write blogs in LaTeX.</description></item></channel></rss>