<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Migration to Hugo on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/categories/migration-to-hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Migration to Hugo on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 20:45:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/categories/migration-to-hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloudfront and TLS</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-14-cloudfront-and-tls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 20:45:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-14-cloudfront-and-tls/</guid><description>&lt;p>I finally decided to cave in and take advantage of the Amazon Cloudfront free TLS certificate. I know I will end up paying more than what I already do but I pay few bucks each month. Each month I pay one dollar for two hosted zones and another dollar or so for the bandwidth. Even if I was still in my home country, I would have been able to pay this as it is less than a large pizza even where I lived.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in free hosting alternatives, you can use &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Github-pages&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/tutorials/hosting-on-bitbucket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitbucket&lt;/a> or just go with the excellent &lt;a href="https://gitlab.com/pages/hugo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gitlab-Pages&lt;/a> (which supports Hugo and whole lot of other static website generators natively).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took me a lot of tries and probably burning a good amount of money on Cloudfront invalidation requests (otherwise I had to wait for a day or so to see the changes) but it finally worked. The trick was to setup the origin policy during creation of the distribution as it cannot be modified through the web portal after that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burp part five is still on hold for now because I am doing something else.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hugo Octopress Update</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-03-hugo-octopress-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 13:13:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-03-hugo-octopress-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have made a good number of changes to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/hugo-octopress" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo-Octopress&lt;/a> theme. As I have been using the theme more and more, I have realized there were a bunch of bugs (some were pointed out on Github).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from Bugs, I had hardcoded too many settings in the theme. For example, modifying the text in the sidebar could only be accomplished by changing the sidebar template. Ideally user should not need to modify anything in the theme and it should be customizable by just using the config file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end I created a bunch of issues on Github and then closed them myself. I am not quite sure if this is correct &lt;code>git&lt;/code> but eh :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Archive Page in Hugo</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-14-archive-page-in-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:52:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-14-archive-page-in-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a re-hash of my answer on Hugo forums about creating a custom archive page. You can see the answer &lt;a href="https://discuss.gohugo.io/t/blog-archives-page/2577/16" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creating a custom archive page in Hugo is pretty simple. I think there are better ways to do this but this works as of version 0.15.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Octopress to Hugo</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 22:58:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/" title="Why Hugo?">my previous post&lt;/a> I talked about why I moved from Octopress to Hugo. You can also see the last archive of my Octopress blog (previously a private repo on Bitbucket) on &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Octopress-Blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">github&lt;/a> and this is the new site. If I had wanted to use an already existing Hugo theme, it would have not taken more than a few hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I am going to talk about how I managed the migration and any interesting things that I encountered in the process. I will also introduce the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/hugo-octopress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo-Octopress&lt;/a> theme (you are looking at it), which is the classic Octopress theme ported to Hugo. If you like what you see, please go ahead and use it. If there are any issues please use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Hugo-Octopress/issues" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Github issue tracker&lt;/a> or contact me another way. I will try my best to fix them but please remember that I am not a developer and do not know much about css :).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Hugo?</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 20:22:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>As you may have noticed (well no one reads this so I am fine), I have moved from &lt;a href="http://octopress.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Octopress&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo&lt;/a>. I have been trying to make this change for a while but due to laziness and some other matters it did not happen. I am going to talk about why I decided on the move and what I did. In then ext post I will talk about my migration from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>