<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Update on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in Update on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 01:37:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking for Apps to Proxy</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-05-09-looking-for-apps-to-proxy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 01:37:41 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-05-09-looking-for-apps-to-proxy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since Burp part four and I want to continue writing these. It's time to actually proxy applications. However I have three problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was too busy at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could not find a lot of interesting applications that are interesting to proxy and can showcase different Burp functionalities that we talked about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found some interesting applications but there were security vulns so I am going through disclosure (unfortunately I may never be able to release them publicly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last point was a surprise, these are decently popular apps and I could not believe that no one has looked at them before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I will continue soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meanwhile, Burp version &lt;code&gt;1.7&lt;/code&gt; has been &lt;a href="http://releases.portswigger.net/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;. Now we have Burp projects. Instead of saving the state everyday, we can use one project file that contains all the items. Pretty cool. Some of the items have changed, especially options. Now it has &lt;code&gt;User Options&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Project Options&lt;/code&gt; but the options by themselves are still there.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Hugo?</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 20:22:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed (well no one reads this so I am fine), I have moved from &lt;a href="http://octopress.org" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I have been trying to make this change for a while but due to laziness and some other matters it did not happen. I am going to talk about why I decided on the move and what I did. In then ext post I will talk about my migration from Octopress to Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fireeye's FLARE Challenge</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2014-09-02-fireeyes-flare-challenge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2014-09-02-fireeyes-flare-challenge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been a while. I know I should have updated more frequently but lazyness prevails.&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, I was busy doing Fireeye's FlARE challenges for a month or so (it was depressing to see people finish in 10 hours :). You can find the challenges at &lt;a href="http://flare-on.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;http://flare-on.com&lt;/a&gt;. I learned a lot doing them. They will release solutions in 2 weeks. I am also working on a writeup which I will release then. I think it will be interesting as it will be a n00b's perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Update Inc</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-20-update-inc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-20-update-inc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, I transferred my domain from my last provider, it has not taken effect yet.
Also, I need to start populating the website with relevant stuff. Hang on, I will be back &lt;strong&gt;soon ™&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>