<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/categories/octopress/</link><description>Recent content in Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 23:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/categories/octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Image Popup and Octopress</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2015-07-26-image-popup-and-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 23:02:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2015-07-26-image-popup-and-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: I have migrated the blog to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo&lt;/a> and I do not use this anymore. However, it is still in the repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally realized that I need an image popup plugin. The image plugins that I usually use do not support this. They are fine for normal images but not for larger ones. When I see a screenshot of a tool, I want to be able to zoom in. In my quest I looked at a few plugins and methods and finally decided to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/ctdk/octopress-image-popup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://github.com/ctdk/octopress-image-popup&lt;/a>. It creates resized thumbnails automatically and the installation procedure is short and simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it did not work for me out of the box. I created a test post with just an image and while the plugin worked, there are things that I did not like about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Update Inc</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-20-update-inc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-20-update-inc/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, I transferred my domain from my last provider, it has not taken effect yet.
Also, I need to start populating the website with relevant stuff. Hang on, I will be back &lt;strong>soon ™&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MarkDown and Cookie Clicker</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-15-markdown-and-cookie-clicker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-15-markdown-and-cookie-clicker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Markdown looks like an easy-ish language to start (probably not so easy to master of course).
Although compared to writing LaTeX source, it is a breeze. During my last year at JHU I started writing the reports and what not directly into LaTeX,
I think using MarkDown for blogging and MS Office at work is going to take away my old skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a side note, I am now up to around 500 million cookies per second (CpS) in
&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://orteil.dashnet.org/cookieclicker/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cookie Clicker&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. I was stuck at 200 million CpS for a week or so until I could start making Antimatter Condensers. I may have missed them before
as they were not visible in the side-bar and I had to scroll down to see them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Octopress</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-14-hello-octopress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-09-14-hello-octopress/</guid><description>&lt;p>** Octopress is here **&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be honest setting it up took a while (I had this feeling that I should set it up on my host but well let's say I am a n00b and am allowed to make mistakes) :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I have to learn markdown which is probably a good thing, unless I can write blog posts in different formats. Note to self: search to see if we can write blogs in LaTeX. That would be too geeky.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>