<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo-Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/tags/hugo-octopress/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo-Octopress on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 13:13:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/tags/hugo-octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo Octopress Update</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-03-hugo-octopress-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 13:13:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-03-hugo-octopress-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have made a good number of changes to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/hugo-octopress" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo-Octopress&lt;/a> theme. As I have been using the theme more and more, I have realized there were a bunch of bugs (some were pointed out on Github).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from Bugs, I had hardcoded too many settings in the theme. For example, modifying the text in the sidebar could only be accomplished by changing the sidebar template. Ideally user should not need to modify anything in the theme and it should be customizable by just using the config file.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end I created a bunch of issues on Github and then closed them myself. I am not quite sure if this is correct &lt;code>git&lt;/code> but eh :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Octopress to Hugo</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 22:58:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-02-from-octopress-to-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-01-31-why-hugo/" title="Why Hugo?">my previous post&lt;/a> I talked about why I moved from Octopress to Hugo. You can also see the last archive of my Octopress blog (previously a private repo on Bitbucket) on &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Octopress-Blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">github&lt;/a> and this is the new site. If I had wanted to use an already existing Hugo theme, it would have not taken more than a few hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I am going to talk about how I managed the migration and any interesting things that I encountered in the process. I will also introduce the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/hugo-octopress/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hugo-Octopress&lt;/a> theme (you are looking at it), which is the classic Octopress theme ported to Hugo. If you like what you see, please go ahead and use it. If there are any issues please use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/parsiya/Hugo-Octopress/issues" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Github issue tracker&lt;/a> or contact me another way. I will try my best to fix them but please remember that I am not a developer and do not know much about css :).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>