<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TLS on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/tags/tls/</link><description>Recent content in TLS on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 20:45:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/tags/tls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloudfront and TLS</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-14-cloudfront-and-tls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 20:45:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-04-14-cloudfront-and-tls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I finally decided to cave in and take advantage of the Amazon Cloudfront free TLS certificate. I know I will end up paying more than what I already do but I pay few bucks each month. Each month I pay one dollar for two hosted zones and another dollar or so for the bandwidth. Even if I was still in my home country, I would have been able to pay this as it is less than a large pizza even where I lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in free hosting alternatives, you can use &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Github-pages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/tutorials/hosting-on-bitbucket/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; or just go with the excellent &lt;a href="https://gitlab.com/pages/hugo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Gitlab-Pages&lt;/a&gt; (which supports Hugo and whole lot of other static website generators natively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a lot of tries and probably burning a good amount of money on Cloudfront invalidation requests (otherwise I had to wait for a day or so to see the changes) but it finally worked. The trick was to setup the origin policy during creation of the distribution as it cannot be modified through the web portal after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burp part five is still on hold for now because I am doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How do I TLS Ciphersuite?</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-11-17-how-do-i-tls-ciphersuite/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2013-11-17-how-do-i-tls-ciphersuite/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;“Should we use RC4 or AES-CBC ?”
This is a legitimate question. Many have heard of the highly publicized attacks against AES-CBC (CRIME, BEAST etc) and lean towards RC4.
If asked (granted no one asks me), my answer would be: If you can control web servers (not feasible in all situations) and users' browsers
(almost impossible), upgrade to TLS 1.2 and go with AES-GCM. However, not many browsers supported these and to be honest, more users trumps loss
of security in many cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>