<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TLS Certificate on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</title><link>https://parsiya.net/tags/tls-certificate/</link><description>Recent content in TLS Certificate on Hackerman's Hacking Tutorials</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 14:42:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsiya.net/tags/tls-certificate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Burp Certificate Authority in Windows Certificate Store</title><link>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-21-installing-burp-certificate-authority-in-windows-certificate-store/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 14:42:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://parsiya.net/blog/2016-02-21-installing-burp-certificate-authority-in-windows-certificate-store/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was writing another blog post and I realized that I keep repeating how to do the same things, so I decided to write some tutorial-ish things and just link them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burp uses custom certificates to Man-in-the-Middle (MitM) the traffic. All of these certificates are signed by Burp's root Certificate Authority (CA). Each installation of Burp generates its own root CA that needs to be installed in the browser or Operating System's certificate store to be recognized properly. Otherwise browsers will return warnings and some thick client applications will not recognize these certificates as valid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each installation of Burp generates its own root CA so it is unlikely that others can gain access to it and sign certificates to MitM your connection. To get the certificate's private key, the attackers need to get to your local machine and if so they have better ways to look at your traffic anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternate instructions by Portswigger: &lt;a href="https://support.portswigger.net/customer/en/portal/articles/1783075-installing-burp-s-ca-certificate-in-your-browser" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://support.portswigger.net/customer/en/portal/articles/1783075-installing-burp-s-ca-certificate-in-your-browser&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instructions on installing/removing Burp's CA in other browsers and devices please use Portswigger's website: &lt;a href="https://support.portswigger.net/customer/en/portal/articles/1783075-installing-burp-s-ca-certificate-in-your-browser" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://support.portswigger.net/customer/en/portal/articles/1783075-installing-burp-s-ca-certificate-in-your-browser&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: These instructions are for Burp version 1.6.37 Pro and 1.6.32 Free. As long as I remember (v1.5) these instructions have not changed, although they may change in the future but I really doubt it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>